HUNTER PIGGOT

Colorado Springs, Colorado · +1-719-432-8466 · hunter.piggot.dev@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/hunterpiggot

Full Stack Software Engineer with over 4 years of experience, leading in the development and maintenance of multiple web applications. Expertise spans a wide range of technologies, including React, JavaScript, TypeScript, .NET, and C#. Led teams in transitioning projects to modern tech stacks, achieving a 25% reduction in build times and a 32% improvement in application performance. Implemented scalable solutions and established coding standards, which improved team productivity by 38%. Currently leading a SaaS platform project focused on data management for archaeologists, enhancing data accuracy through mapping features.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lead Frontend Developer - Chronicle Heritage, Remote

January 2024 - Present

- Led a team of 5 frontend developers in the development of a SaaS platform for field data management, specifically targeting archaeologists for data collection and management.
- Increased team productivity by 38% through effective management, mentoring, and implementation of best practices upon joining the team.
- Designed multiple robust geospatial features that supports the management of thousands of locations, providing capabilities for users to view, edit, and organize site data.
- Spearheaded the transition of the project from Webpack and SASS to Vite and Tailwind CSS; achieved a 25% reduction in build times, enhancing team productivity and facilitating smoother deployment processes for future updates.

Full-Stack Developer - Good Home Renovations, Remote

August 2023 – January 2024

- Spearheaded the creation of an advanced property investment application, streamlining property and team management with integrated financial tools. This innovation led to a 10% reduction in project overruns.
- Engineered a multifunctional repair estimator and flip analysis module, designed for in-depth cost management and profit analysis. Enhanced user experience by enabling data export to Excel and PDF.
- Created the entire application using a modern tech stack, including React, Vite, TypeScript, TailwindCSS on the front-end, and .NET 7.0 for the back-end, ensuring a responsive and user-friendly interface.
- Orchestrated end-to-end project management of SQL Server database and Azure hosting, enabling seamless development, deployment, and maintenance in a cloud environment; optimized performance by 20%.

React Developer - Cazton, Remote

February 2022 – June 2023

- Developed two healthcare web portal front ends from scratch using React, TypeScript, Google Cloud Platform, and Python, leading many parts of the application in data management for a range of medical professionals.
- Exercised Agile Development methodology, collaborating with a diverse team of 25 front-end, back-end, and UI/UX developers, and completed twice the assigned workload, contributing to the team's overall progress.
- Initiated a back-end architectural redesign for data aggregation, leading to a 300% increase in application performance and higher user satisfaction. Collaborated with cross-functional teams to accomplish this improvement.

Full Stack Software Engineer - JKP Group

July 2020 - February 2022

• Developed, and deployed a React front-end and Flask backend application that enabled users to calculate mortgage payments, assess gross equity value, and access a comprehensive first-time homebuyer guide.

EDUCATION

2019 - Arizona State University - Computer Science

2020 - Springboard - Software Engineering

SKILLS

Skills: React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, .NET, C#, GraphQL , jQuery, Flask, Docker, Azure, Vite, Chart.js, PostgreSQL, Tailwind Css, HTML, Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Jenkins, Agile, Mapbox